BARAN KÜÇÜKGÜZEL

kucukguzelbaran@gmail.com https://github.com/bariyu https://www.linkedin.com/in/baran-küçükgüzel-42708476

http://bkucukguzel.me +31 6 38 58 94 81

SUMMARY

I am an enthusiast software engineer with 4 years of experience. I have done software development in different areas. I have worked mostly as a backend engineer and currently working as a backend engineer, but I also have experience building iOS applications and web applications. I am very passionate about software engineering, I try to learn new stuff and grow myself as an engineer every day. I have experience working in big companies and small startups as well. I have a computer engineering degree from one the best programs in Turkey. I am currently working as a Software Developer for Booking.com in Amsterdam, Netherlands.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Booking.com, Amsterdam, Netherlands

April 2017 - Present

Software Developer

Working as a software developer in one of the hotelier facing product teams.
 Mainly working on back-end using Perl also JavaScript time to time. Developing new APIs and services, designing them from scratch and integrating with 3rd parties and existing internal services/applications. Working on both web and mobile backends, almost all of the tech stack is based on Perl. Main technologies I use include Perl, JavaScript, MySQL, Git, Redis, and Java.

ScoreBeyond, Ankara, Turkey - Menlo Park, CA *Software Engineer - Tech Lead*

March 2015 - March 2017

• Worked as a full stack software engineer. Mainly worked on web and mobile applications and their backends. I have developed server-side applications using Python, Go and NodeJS. For front-end, I mainly used React and for mobile development Objective-C and React Native. I also had a lot of responsibilities like rolling-out new software and monitoring/provisioning systems & servers. For the last year, I was also the Tech Lead for a team of 3. Main technologies I have used include Python, Objective-C, Javascript, React, React-Native, MongoDB, Redis, AWS, Git. ScoreBeyond has been acquired by LinkedIn in Jan 2018.

MilSOFT, Ankara, Turkey

Software Engineer

July 2014 - March 2015

 Development of new features/services, improvement, optimization and maintenance of MilSOFT DDS which is a nationally leading implementation of the Object Management Group (OMG)'s Data Distribution Service (DDS) messaging standard for both enterprise and real-time systems. I developed couple services which include a service connecting geographically separated networks and another service which record topics published in a DDS environment to be analyzed/replayed later. Mainly used technologies are C++, Java, MongoDB.

ASELSAN, Ankara, Turkey

Software Engineering Intern

Worked on adding a new feature to the test suite application of the project T129
 ATAK helicopter which logs changes made on tests by test engineers to help
 them document changes much more easily. Used C#.

June 2013 – July 2013

EDUCATION

Middle East Technical University, Ankara, TURKEY

2014 –2016 (dropout)

MSc in Computer Engineering 3.14/4.00

I have taken 6 of 7 required courses then decided not to continue.

Middle East Technical University, Ankara, TURKEY 2009 –2014

B.Eng. in Computer Engineering with High Honors, 3.85/4.00

AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS

Graduated 3rd from the Dept. of Computer Eng., Middle East Technical University

CENG Demo Day (Graduation Project Competition): 1st project among 26 projects

2014

2014

2014

2019

2019

2019

2010 - 2014

LANGUAGES

Turkish – Native

English – Read/write and speak with high proficiency.

COMPUTER SKILLS

Languages: Python, JavaScript, Objective-C, Perl, C/C++/C#, Go, Java

Software/Libraries/Technologies: Distributed Systems, Linux, MySQL, MongoDB, Redis, React, React-Native